Provenance Widgets is an open source
library of modular UI control elements
such as range sliders, select dropdowns,
and checkbox groups. This library tracks
the recency and frequency of a user's
provenance and presents them back to the
user via dynamically overlaid
visualizations. Let me show you how:
Consider this range slider. If I interact
with it a few times by changing the
ranges, our library will add visual scents
at the top, showing an aggregated summary
of what has happened so far.
By default, the color corresponds to
recency and the height corresponds to
frequency.
Clicking on that little footprints icon
reveals a detailed temporal evolution
showing which ranges have been selected
so far, and when. I can filter a subset
of these selections by brushing the Y-axis.
I can also revisit any
selection by simply clicking on the
points or the rectangles corresponding to
that selection. Let's take another
example. This is a single select dropdown
If during the course of analysis I end up
selecting different cities such as New
York, Rome and London, the library can
visually tell me each options
interaction, recency and frequency.
In the detailed view, it can tell me
exactly when I selected a particular
option. Here it looks like London was
consistently selected throughout the
analysis and Istanbul was not selected at
all. Just like before, I can filter my
interaction provenance using this range
slider and revisit any state by clicking
on the rectangle representing that state.
Provenance widget supports a variety of
UI controls like single sliders, multi
select drop downs, radio button groups,
checkbox groups and text inputs. The
library is open sourced and available at
github.com/ProvenanceWidgets.
We hope our library helps application
developers build custom provenance aware
systems with ease.